Guide to the Ruth Stephan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1915-1974; Series I; 20.64; (51 boxes)
  - Subject Files
    - Childhood - "My Daily Collection" (Box 36)
    - Christmas card lists, 1949-1960; 2 (Box 36)
    - Christmas cards, 1949-1957; 4 (Box 37)
    - Christmas cards from contributors, 1950 (Box 37)
    - Christmas cards from friends, 1952-1957; 2 (Box 37)
    - Christmas cards from friends (continued), 1952-1957 (Box 38)
    - Christmas and New Year correspondence, 1934-1973 (Box 38)
    - Clippings (Box 38)
    - Contributions, 1955-1959 (Box 38)
    - Correspondence - friends, 1951-1952; 2 (Box 38)
    - Correspondence - friends (continued), 1953-1956; 5 (Box 39)
    - Correspondence - friends (continued), 1956-1958; 7 (Box 40)
    - Correspondence - friends (continued), 1958-1960; 8 (Box 41)
    - Correspondence - friends (continued), 1963; 3 (Box 42)
    - Correspondence - friends, relatives, 4 (Box 42)
    - Curly Corner (Box 42)
    - Grand Detour players (Box 43)
    - Italy (Box 43)
    - Japan, 1961 (Box 43)
    - Mankind - Black Issue 1970, correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 43)
    - Memberships (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 (Box 43)
    - Northwestern University (Box 43)
    - Paintings - sculpture (Box 43)
    - Peru (Box 43)
    - Philanthropies (Box 43)
    - Program notes (Box 44)
    - Records (78 and LPs), compiled notes, 1956 March (Box 44)
    - School certificates (Box 44)
    - 17th Century correspondence, bills, 1971-1972 (Box 44)
    - 17th Century paid bills (Box 44)
    - 17th Century translations (Box 44)
    - Stephan, Ruth (Box 44)
    - Travel notes - Europe, 1951-1953 (Box 44)
    - Trinidad (Box 44)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1956-1965 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence on Ruth Stephan's desk at time of her death, 1971-1973; 3 (Box 45)
  - Family correspondence
    - Family correspondence, 1938-1941; 15 (Box 46)
    - Family correspondence (continued), 1943-1953; 16 (Box 47)
    - Family correspondence (continued), 1953-1959; 16 (Box 48)
    - Family correspondence (continued), 1959-1973; 10 (Box 49)
    - Family records (Box 49)
    - Stephan, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick, 1940-1963; 2 (Box 49)
    - Stephan, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick (continued), 1940-1963; 4 (Box 50)
    - Letters to John Stephan, 1938-1973 (Box 50)
  - Correspondence, 5 (Box 51)
    Restricted until January 1, 2024. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
- Writings, 1936-1974; Series II; 25; (64 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by title, with poetry and untitled works filed at the end.
  Series II. Writings contains notes, research files, drafts, and proofs of Stephan's poetry, prose, and editorial work, as well as production files for an incomplete film.
  - "The Black Americans in changing pattern", 1969-1970; 5 (Box 52)
  - "Borromini", [1968-1973]
    - Manuscripts, 8 (Box 53)
    - Source material, 7 (Box 54)
    - Index cards (Box 55)
  - "Christina, or, the royal road to Rome", 1950-1971
    - Research files, 9 (Box 56)
    - Research files (continued), 12 (Box 57)
    - Research files (continued), 10 (Box 58)
    - Research files (continued), 8 (Box 59)
    - Research files (continued), 9 (Box 60)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 61)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 62)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 63)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 64)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 65)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 66)
    - Research files (bound translations) (Box 67)
    - Research files (continued), 7 (Box 68)
    - Research files (continued), 8 (Box 69)
    - Research files (continued), 7 (Box 70)
    - Index cards (Box 71)
    - Index cards (continued) (Box 72)
    - Index cards (continued) (Box 73)
    - Index cards (continued) (Box 74)
  - "Daitokuji Diary", [1964]
    - Drafts, 4 (Box 75)
    - Objects (Box 76)
  - "The Flight", 1950-1971
    - Drafts, notes, working pages, 8 (Box 77)
    - Drafts, notes, working pages (continued), 7 (Box 78)
    - Typescripts, 7 (Box 79)
    - Typescripts (continued), 5 (Box 80)
    - Clippings, etc., 8 (Box 81)
    - Page proofs, 2 (Box 82)
    - Page proofs (continued) (Box 83)
  - "Jegerson's Daughter", 1965-1966
    - Drafts, 6 (Box 84)
    - Drafts (continued), 6 (Box 85)
    - Drafts (continued), 6 (Box 86)
    - Drafts (continued), 2 (Box 87)
  - Lafcadio Hearn Memorial, 1938-1950; 6 (Box 87)
  - "My Crown, My Love", [1956-1961]
    - Drafts, 6 (Box 88)
    - Drafts (continued), 7 (Box 89)
    - Drafts (continued), 9 (Box 90)
    - Drafts (continued), 7 (Box 91)
    - Correspondence, etc., 4 (Box 92)
    - Page proofs, 2 (Box 93)
    - Page proofs (continued) (Box 94)
  - "The Singing Mountaineers: Songs and Tales of the Quechua People", 1945-1958
    - Drafts, 8 (Box 95)
    - Drafts (continued), 8 (Box 96)
    - Correspondence, translations, 7 (Box 97)
  - "A Spoken Anthology of American Literature", 1959-1966
    - Drafts, 6 (Box 98)
    - Drafts (continued), 5 (Box 99)
    - Drafts (continued), 5 (Box 100)
    - Correspondence, 2 (Box 100)
    - Texts (Box 100)
    - Work sheets, etc., 2 (Box 100)
    - Sound recordings
      Existence and Location of Originals
      See: Series III. Audiovisual Material, Box 140
  - Poetry, 1936-1967
    - "Various Poems"
      - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 101)
      - Drafts (Box 101)
      - Hardcover copy with drawings by Ossip Zadkine (Box 101)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 (Box 101)
      - Page proofs, 1963; 4 (Box 101)
    - "The Arriving Saints" (Box 102)
    - "Prelude to Poetry" (Box 102)
    - Early work, 1936-1946; 3 (Box 102)
    - Finished poems (Box 102)
    - Galleys for "Jamaica Jingles" (Box 102)
    - Jingles, 1936-1941 (Box 102)
    - Journal, 1940 (Box 102)
    - New Year poetry (Box 102)
    - New Year poetry (continued), 3 (Box 103)
    - 1965 poetry - comments (Box 103)
    - Notebook (Box 103)
    - Poetry and Ordinary Man (Box 103)
    - Published work, 1936-1952 (Box 103)
    - Unpublished work, 2 (Box 103)
    - Songs and exercises (Box 103)
    - Sonnets, 1941-1945; 2 (Box 103)
    - Winged notes (Box 103)
    - Women poets (Box 103)
    - Drafts, 1945-1960; 3 (Box 104)
    - Drafts, notes, 1937-1968; 8 (Box 105)
    - Drafts, notes (continued), 1945-1973; 7 (Box 106)
    - Notes, 1939-1946; 7 (Box 107)
    - Notes (continued), 1939-1967; 10 (Box 108)
    - "Treasure Mirror", 1971-1973 (Box 109)
    - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, 1947-1963; 2 (Box 109)
  - Other Writings and Projects, 1935-1971
    - Alfred Hayes notes (Box 110)
    - "The Art of Communication" notes, 1943-1946 (Box 110)
    - Autobiographical sketch for midcentury authors (Box 110)
    - "Chicago Learns About World Affairs" (Box 110)
    - Children's plays, 1939-1940; 2 (Box 110)
    - Children's verse, 1938-1939 (Box 110)
    - Cinema correspondence, scripts, notes (Box 110)
    - "Domestic Economy" (Box 110)
    - Dorothy Livesay notes (Box 110)
    - Editorials (Box 110)
    - "Fearing", 1943 (Box 110)
    - Friends of Literature award dinner, 1957 April 27 (Box 110)
    - Icelandic poetry, [1943] (Box 110)
    - "The Idea", 2 (Box 110)
    - Ideas (Box 110)
    - Kuo Hsi (Film), circa 1974
      - Chinese and Japanese paintings, Wabi introduction (Box 111)
      - Crawford, John M. Jr. (Box 111)
      - Freer Gallery (Box 111)
      - General, 2 (Box 111)
      - Metropolitan (Box 111)
      - National Palace Museum - Taiwan (Box 111)
      - Production, 4 (Box 111)
    - Letter for "Festschrift for Marianne Moore's 77th birthday" (Box 111)
    - Literary notes for Walgreen book, 1952-1964; 2 (Box 111)
    - Lyrics (Box 111)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1971; 6 (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous plays, 1936-1943; 3 (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous (continued), 1949-1971; 2 (Box 113)
    - "My Seventeenth Century" (Box 113)
    - Notes, 5 (Box 113)
    - Notes (continued), 5 (Box 114)
    - Novel - after publication (Box 114)
    - No. 3 Atlantic, 1939-1943; 2 (Box 114)
    - Poetry center (Box 114)
    - "Prelude to Poetry" (Box 114)
    - "Profit", 1940-1955 (Box 114)
    - "Profit" (continued), 1940-1955 (Box 115)
    - Published articles (Box 115)
    - Unpublished articles, 1937-1939 (Box 115)
    - Quotes (Box 115)
    - Rafael Alberti notes (Box 115)
    - Repairing of Ryoko-in Temple (Box 115)
    - Selected list of living American poets and critics, 1950 (Box 115)
    - "Six Persimmons" article (Box 115)
    - "Six Persimmons" correspondence (Box 115)
    - Translations - Karen Boye (Box 115)
    - "Travelers in a Secret Country" by Carrera Andrade and Kemp (Box 115)
    - "The Walgreen Story" - material, 1935-1958; 2 (Box 115)
    - Winged notes (Box 115)
    - Zen priests and their six persimmons (Box 115)
- Audiovisual Material, undated; Series III; 0.6; (3 boxes)
  Arrranged alphabetically.
  Series III contains a print of Stephan's film documentary Zen in Ryoko-in (released in 1971), as well as sound recordings documenting her time in India and her work on The Spoken Anthology of American Literature.
  Material in this series is restricted. Access copies may be requested. Please consult with Access Services for more information.
  - "India." 1/4" reel to reel sound recordings (2), undated (Box 116)
  - "On a Poetry Center. Ruth Stephan." 1 cassette tape, undated (Box 140)
  - The Spoken Anthology of American Literature. 13 sound recordings (3 inch, 4 inch tapes), undated (Box 140)
  - Zen in Ryoko-in. 16mm film reels (2), undated (Box 117)
- Other Papers, 1928-1972; Series IV; 10.89; (29 boxes)
  Arranged by format.
  Series IV. Other Papers consists of diaries, notebooks, engagement calendars, address books, photographs, and other material documenting Stephan's life.
  Diaries in Boxes 118-121 are restricted until January 1, 2024.
  - Diaries, 6 (Box 118)
  - Diaries (continued), 5 (Box 119)
  - Diaries (continued), 6 (Box 120)
  - Diaries (continued), 6 (Box 121)
  - Awards (Box 122)
  - Dart custody case, 1937-1949; 2 (Box 122)
  - Essays, 3 (Box 123)
  - Gift of books, 1957-1959; 3 (Box 123)
  - Keats book (Box 124)
  - Invitations (Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous, 5 (Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous (continued) (Box 125)
  - Miscellaneous (continued), 2 (Box 126)
  - Notebooks/engagement books, 3 (Box 126)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 5 (Box 127)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 5 (Box 128)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 5 (Box 129)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 5 (Box 130)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 5 (Box 131)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 5 (Box 132)
  - Notebooks/engagement books (continued), 3 (Box 133)
  - Notecards with names and addresses, 2 (Box 133)
  - Photographs, 2 (Box 134)
  - Photographs (continued), 4 (Box 135)
  - Poetry center - notes (Box 136)
  - Postcards (Box 136)
  - Print block (unidentified) (Box 136)
  - Printed Ephemera, 9 (Box 137)
  - Printed Ephemera (continued), 1928-1972; 6 (Box 138)
  - Printed Ephemera (continued), 2 (Box 139)
  - Color slides, mainly of India (Box 140)
    General note
    Sound recordings from Series III. stored in same box.
  - Subject Files
    - India, 8 (Box 141)
    - India (continued), 6 (Box 142)
    - India (continued), 6 (Box 143)
    - India (continued), 3 (Box 144)
    - Tiger's Eye, 1947-1964; 6 (Box 145)
  - Walgreen lectures, 2 (Box 146)
  - Warwick Woods pamphlets (Box 146)
- Oversize, 1.83; (2 boxes)
  - Photographs, artwork, clippings, 7 (Box 147)
  - Awards, Borromini source material, miscellaneous, 4 (Box 148)